PENNY:
Previously on The Big Bang Theory:
-This is just a minor setback.
-No, it's not, okay?
I've been out here for,
like, ten years.
-I have nothing to show for it.
-Well, you have me.
I do have you.
Mmm.
Leonard Hofstadter,
will you marry me?
Um...
Did you seriously just say...umm?
-It's an outrage.
- I know.
The university, they think
they can do whatever they want.
We just have to sit
there and take it.
You need to let it go, Sheldon.
You work tirelessly for someone
and this is what you get.
Oh, my God! They're just making
you use your vacation days!
But I don't want a vacation.
Okay, listen, I don't mean to
diminish what you're going through,
but I'm a little
distracted right now.
Oh, this again?
So, Penny proposed,
you didn't say yes,
and now you think you may
have lost her love forever.
How does this compare to me being
forced to relax for a few days?
-It doesn't!
-Thank you!
I'm gonna go talk to Penny.
I'm going to go inside,
put on my coziest pajamas,
curl up with a good book and wait
for this nightmare to be over.
(EXHALES)
Penny.
Sorry.
-Hi.
-Hey.
Look, I'm sorry I
didn't text you back.
I just needed
some time to think.
-Okay.
-Here. Come in.
Look, if you want
to break up, just say it.
-Leonard--
-No, no, no. I take it back.
Don't say it.
Just hate me, but stay with me.
It worked for my parents.
Listen, I don't want
to break up with you.
Oh. Okay.
Good, good.
So it's cool if I cry a little?
-Yeah, I probably wouldn't.
-Yeah.
Look, you did the right thing
last night. I was a mess.
I was just frustrated because
my career is going nowhere.
Look, I get it,
and I want you to know
that I support
whatever you want to do.
Great, because
I've been thinking,
if I really want this
acting thing to work,
I need to focus all my energy on it.
And to do that,
I should quit waitressing
at The Cheesecake Factory.
Wow.
-That's a big step.
- I know.
So, you know, before
making any rash--
- I already quit.
-And I support you.
J (THEME SONG) 7
Come on, take me
to work with you.
No. You're on vacation.
Please? What if there's a big
breakthrough in science today
and I'm not there to see it?
Do you really think
there's gonna be a breakthrough
-without you there to do it?
-No. I was just tricking you.
Bye.
Leonard, wait!
-Take me with you.
-No!
-Please.
-Too bad. I'm coming with you.
-Sheldon, stay!
-But--
- I said stay!
I'm going to work.
Do not follow me.
(WHIMPERS)
(SIGHS)
BERNADETTE: Hey, Stuart.
-Hey.
-Sorry. Did I startle you?
Yes, but at this point, pretty
much any customer does.
-What can I do for you?
-Well, I need a little help.
I accidentally destroyed one of
Howard's comic books this morning,
-and was hoping I could replace it.
-Wow. What happened?
Batman got his ass kicked
by my curling iron.
Don't let The Riddler know that.
It's a comic book joke.
Or maybe it's not.
-Do you have this one?
-Well, it's pretty rare.
Can you give me a few
days to track it down?
I was kind of hoping to get it
before Howie comes home from work.
-What's the hurry?
-Well, he's always saying
I should be more careful
with my curling iron,
and it seems like
a dangerous precedent
to let him think he can be right.
Well, I'll do what I can,
but I can't make any promises.
You know, I do work
at a pharmaceutical company.
If you can make this happen today,
I can hook you up with anxiety
medication, antidepressants.
Really.
Do you have any of these?
Hello, Mr. Rat Brain.
Not so bitey without the rest of the
rat to back us up now, are we?
-(TAPS ON DOOR)
-Anybody home?
Hey, what brings you guys here?
Well, we were just on our way
to lunch and wanted to see
-if you'd like to join.
-Why?
Because Sheldon's
not here this week,
and you don't think I
have any other options?
I'm just kidding.
I'll get my purse.
Hi, Amy. I... Oh.
I'm sorry. I didn't know
you had any company.
That's okay.
Bert, this is Howard and Rajesh.
Guys, this is Bert.
-Hey. Good to see you.
-Hey.
Anyway, I wanted to show you
this tourmalinated quartz
that we got in the lab.
This is so pretty.
Bert works for the
geology department.
Yeah. You know what geologists
and Bon Jovi have in common?
You're both into rock?
Yeah.
-Well, see ya.
-You forgot your quartz.
Oh, it's okay.
I want you to have it.
Bye.
He's nice.
Yeah, he's nice
because he likes you.
What?
-No, he doesn't.
-He brought you a pretty rock.
So? He does that every day--
Oh.
You know, if you'd
rather skip lunch
and hang out with your boyfriend,
Bert, it's totally okay.
He's not my boyfriend.
Are you sure?
He's tall, pale and awkward.
That sounds like your type.
Should someone as lonely as you
really be making fun of me?
Yeah, grow up, Howard. God.
What do I do?
I don't want to hurt his feelings.
Maybe the problem is
he thinks you're available.
Does he know
you're dating Sheldon?
I guess it hasn't come up.
There you go.
And does Sheldon know
you're dating Sheldon?
I'm sorry. Who are you dating?
Yeah, knock it off, Howard!
-Oh, hey, Sheldon.
-(DEJECTEDLY) Hello.
You okay?
I'm on vacation.
What do you think?
Why are you sitting
in the stairwell?
Leonard told me to stay.
Oh.
Well, good boy.
-Where are you going?
- I have a ton of errands to run.
I need to make copies of my
headshot, send them off to agents
and sign up for a new
acting class.
-Well, have fun.
-Okay.
(WHIMPERS SOFTLY)
-You want to come with me?
-Really?
Come on, boy. Come on.
Let's go. Let's go.
Get in the car. Come on.
All right, thanks a lot.
They have one at Capital Comics.
-That's great.
-No, it's not. I hate that place.
Guy who owns it is a jerk.
He's always making me
feel bad about myself.
That's terrible.
What's the address?
You know, why don't I
just take you there?
That way, I can make sure
he doesn't rip you off.
Thanks, but I don't
want you to close up.
I mean, won't you lose business?
Sorry. That was mean.
Penny really quit
The Cheesecake Factory?
-Yeah.
-So what is she doing today?
I don't know. She already
thinks I don't support this,
so if I call, it might look like
I'm checking up on her.
-Well, do you support this?
-Of course I do.
She's a great actress.
I'm proud she's taking this risk.
-That's nice.
-You bought that? Great!
I got to call her before
I forget how I said it.
Hey.
-Hi. What's up?
-How's it going?
You taking Hollywood by storm?
Actually,
I'm at The Cheesecake Factory.
You got your job back.
That is great news.
I didn't want to say anything,
but you are making the right choice.
To plunge yourself into debt right
now would be literally insane.
Yeah. I'm just
returning my uniform.
And I support you.
MAN: Before we begin your
guided meditation,
close your eyes and picture
yourself in a peaceful environment.
Okay.
I'm inside the CERN super collider.
Now, take a deep, relaxing
breath in through your nose.
And let it out.
Wow. Didn't see that coming.
In.
Let me guess.
And out.
What was I gonna do?
Two "ins" in a row?
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
-Where's my lemonade?
- I didn't get it.
A fitting swan song
to your career as a waitress
to forget my order one last time.
Do you think quitting
my job was a mistake?
Do you see me drinking lemonade?
No. I'm serious.
Why do you ask?
Because Leonard just pissed me off.
Am I being an idiot or not?
No, I don't think you are.
Really?
The best way to achieve
a goal is to devote 100 percent
of your time and energy to it.
When I decided I was
going to be a physicist,
I didn't take some other job
in case it didn't work out.
Which wasn't easy because
there was a lot of pressure
from Ms. Pierson for me
to be chalk monitor that year.
Thank you.
I needed to hear that.
Why can't Leonard understand it?
Because he's not like us, Penny.
We're dreamers.
Yeah, I need to start cracking the
window when I leave you in the car.
Hey.
Hello, Bert.
So, anyway, there's this big
rock and mineral show
next week in Santa Monica and--
Listen... Bert, before you
say anything else, |I...
I have a boyfriend.
Oh. This is awkward.
You thought I was gonna ask you
to go with me to the mineral show.
Weren't you?
Yeah.
That's very nice of you,
but I do have a boyfriend.
That's what you all say.
You just don't want
to go out with me
because I have
an off-putting personality.
No, that's not true.
My boyfriend has
an off-putting personality, too.
Way worse than you.
Don't worry. I'm used to it.
I mean, I'm big and weird
and funny-looking
and no one ever wants
to do anything with me.
Don't say that.
It's okay.
I know I'm a monster.
No, Bert, come on.
I'd love to go to the
mineral show with you.
Sweet. It's a date.
-No, it's not.
-BERT: Too late!
Wow.
Yeah. Haven't seen this
many people in my store
since that Korean church bus
crashed through my front window.
-Hey! Stuart!
-Jesse.
Haven't seen you in forever.
Look how gray you've gotten.
My hair's exactly
the same color as always.
No, I was talking about your skin.
Look... my friend here
needs a comic book--
Ooh! And she went into
your store by mistake.
Good thing there was no
one there to see you.
What do you need?
Oh, yeah, yeah. I got this.
Right over here.
Even you, Sweatpants?
Free popcorn.
Can I offer you a coffee?
-Espresso? Latte?
-No, thanks.
How about you, Stu?
Mocha? Scone?
Directions to the
nearest soup kitchen?
-Hey.
-I'm just kidding.
He knows where the soup kitchen is.
It's on Merton Avenue.
I don't think I like the way
you're treating my friend.
Sorry.
-You want the book or not?
-Not from you.
Let's go, Stuart.
You know something, Jesse?
You may have a
successful business
and the kind of pink complexion
that comes with good nutrition...
but I have something
more important.
-What's that?
-Friendship.
Which I would trade in a
heartbeat for all of this.
The mineral and rock show?
That would be awful even
without Bert.
So what am I supposed to do now?
Prepare your uterus
for his gigantic offspring?
This isn't funny.
I'm gonna have to
tell him the truth:
that even if I didn't
have a boyfriend,
I wouldn't be interested in him.
I've heard those
words so many times.
From Linda Nosenchuck,
Tammy Rosenworcel...
Padma Kapur, Neha Chowdury...
Marci Grossman,
Lisa Mazzarino...
-Megan Pincus...
-Tammy Cho...
Who was that girl
from our Starbucks?
-Arlene Russell!
-Yes! Arlene!
She wrote "no way"
on both our cappuccinos.
Poor Bert.
That guy's got a rough
afternoon ahead of him.
Well, how would you want a girl
to tell you she wasn't interested?
I guess, uh, I'd like her to sit me
down, look me in the eye and say,
"I was wrong. I love you."
And then maybe she could
touch me in a special way.
That's how you reject a guy.
Okay, I don't have time for this.
I'm just gonna go find him
and be brutally honest.
-No, don't.
-He'll be so upset.
He'll probably climb
up the Empire State Building
and start swatting at planes.
You want us to talk to him?
Really? You would do that?
Sure. We've both been in his shoes.
We'll let him down with
compassion and respect.
-Thank you.
-Let's go.
So we tell him
she's a lesbian, right?
Of course we tell him
she's a lesbian.
And hold three...
two... one.
Very good.
Now let's try Warrior.
And hold.
I've read that there are great
yogis who have such mastery
over their bodies they can draw
water in through their genitals.
Yeah, well, I don't think we're
gonna get to do that today.
Too bad.
It seems like a good way
to drink a milk shake
without getting brain freeze.
Oh, hey.
And now we go to Reverse Warrior.
How did she get you to do yoga?
Well, to be honest,
I thought she said "Yoda."
I'm helping him relax because,
unlike you, he supports me.
Oh, How many times
do I have to say it?
- I support you.
-Sheldon, take a break.
Namaste.
Okay, if you support me,
what was with that phone call?
Fine. I'm not sure
you should have quit.
But if you care so
much what I think,
why didn't you ask me
before you did it?
Oh, so now I need
your permission?
Would you have asked me
before you quit your job?
Yes. I thought we were
in the kind of relationship
where we make decisions together.
If I'm wrong,
then maybe we need to talk
about the kind of relationship
we're actually in.
Yeah, well, maybe we do.
I'm willing to if you guys are.
Can we please
have some privacy?
No.
I'm as much a part of this
relationship as you two,
and I think it's high time we
put all our cards on the table.
Yeah. For example,
where is this going?
Are you two ever getting married?
And, if so, where will we all live?
Have you thought about that?
-No.
-Penny?
OK, wait. What are we doing?
For some reason,
we're planning a future
where we both live
with Sheldon forever.
Good. Now we're getting somewhere.
Look, I know you think I'm being
reckless, and you might be right,
but I need to take this shot.
No kidding. Despite what it says
on her résumé, she is no longer 22.
I swear, I am on your side.
You keep saying you're on my
side, but you don't act like it.
He does that to me, too.
Why do we put up with it?
Listen, I could never do
what you're doing, okay?
-I would be terrified.
-Well, it's scary for me, too.
I'm fine with it.
My point is, just because I couldn't
do it doesn't mean you shouldn't.
And I'm proud of you.
Okay. Thank you.
Well, to celebrate
this reconciliation,
let's all share a milk shake.
Penny, you'll need a straw.
-You're back.
-Yes, I am!
There's a few more things
I want to say to you.
Stuart's store is just fine, and he's
a much nicer person than you are,
and if you still have that comic,
I'd like to buy it right now!
No problem.
Oh, you want a latte
while you wait?
No, I don't want a latte!
I want a cappuccino
and a blueberry scone!
- I only have chocolate chip.
-Well, that sounds even better!
Thanks for coming to the
mineral and rock show with me.
We're sorry Amy didn't want to go.
Really, really sorry.
Nah, who needs her
when I have you guys?
CHANTING: Rock show!
Rock show! Rock show!
Rock show!
s (THEME MUSIC) &
(English - SDH)